Finding Aid for George Cacioppo papers, 1939-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George Cacioppo papers 1939-1985
Cacioppo, George.
(in 22 boxes)
12 linear feet
2009045 Aa 2
This collection contains sketches, manuscripts, printed music and writings by George Cacioppo, American composer, founder of the ONCE group, and faculty member at the University of Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
A majority of the collection was bequeathed to the University of Michigan School of Music by George Cacioppo in 1984. Some memorabilia was donated to the School by William Albright in 1986. All of these materials were given to the Music Library (donor 9112 ). The collection was transferred to the Bentley Historical Library in 2008.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
George E. Cacioppo, American composer, was born in Monroe, Michigan on September 24, 1926, and died in Ann Arbor, Michigan on April 8, 1984. He studied with Ross Lee Finney at the University of Michigan and obtained his B.Mus. in 1951 and M.Mus. in 1952. Subsequently, he worked at Tanglewood and was awarded a Koussevitsky grant for study with Leon Kirchner in 1959. In 1960 he studied privately with Roberto Gerhard in Ann Arbor.
In 1961 Cacioppo co-founded the ONCE group and was an active organizer of and participant in the ONCE Festival from 1961 to 1968. The ONCE group produced annual concerts of premieres by both established and avant garde composers. The festivals established Ann Arbor as an international center of avant garde music in the sixties.
Cacioppo worked as a studio engineer at the WUOM radio station. He also occasionally taught composition at the University of Michigan School of Music. His works are published by BMI Canada, Percussion Music Inc. (N.Y.), and Berandol Press (Toronto, Canada).
Cacioppo was one of the first composers to explore the aesthetic known as "piece as process" with indeterminate notation: a composition unfolds anew each time it is performed. His interest in astronomy was reflected in many of his compositions, including one of his most famous compositions, Cassiopeia (1962). The piece is in indeterminate notation, based on the shape of the constellation Cassiopeia. His works are performed nationwide in new music concerts.
The collection contains sketches, manuscripts, printed music and writings by George Cacioppo, as well as correspondence (business and family), press clippings, programs and ONCE Festival memorabilia. The materials were arranged in logical sequence rather than "original order" so that research and performance of the materials would be facilitated. Details of the series arrangement have been provided below. Books and music by others have been removed from the collection, but lists of these materials have been retained. Many of Cacioppo's manuscripts were reproduced in different ways. The term "reproductions" was used in the finding aid to refer to ozalid copies and photocopies. Duplicates of the reproductions were removed.
Subjects:
Aleatory music.; Cacioppo, George.; Music--United States--20th century.; ONCE Festival (Ann Arbor, Mich.); University of Michigan--Faculty.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Cacioppo, George.; Composers--United States.; Electronic music--United States.; Musicians--United States.; ONCE Festival (Ann Arbor, Mich.); University of Michigan--Faculty.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Aleatory music.; Piano music.
Contributors: Sound Recordings
Albright, William.; Carpenter, Kurt.; Gordon, Nancy C.; Lifschitz, Max.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Manuscripts and Printed Music
  - Adagio con moto. For orchestra. (Box 1)
    (Incomplete)
    (Folder 1/1)
  - The Advance of the fungii. For wind instruments., 9 folders (Box 2)
    (Folders 2/1-9)
  - Bestiary 1: Eingang: for soprano and percussion.--New York: Music for Percussion circa 1976 (Box 1)
    (Performance notes included.)
    (Folder 1/2)
  - Cassiopeia. For piano. (Box 3)
    (Folder 3/1)
  - Chartless. For voice and piano. (Box 1)
    (Folder 1/3)
  - [Concertos, piano] (Box 3)
    (Star charts used for piano concerto)
    (Folder 3/2)
  - Dream concert: for organ, voice(s) & small percussion orchestra., 2 folders (Box 3)
    (Folders 3/3-4)
  - Elegy. (Box 3)
    (See Two pieces for orchestra.)
  - Fantasy. For violin and piano. (Box 3)
    (Folder 3/5)
  - Festival overture. (Box 3)
  - The Fly. For voice and piano. (Box 1)
    (Folder 1/4)
  - The half-moon westers low. For voice and piano., 2 folders (Box 1)
    (Folders 1/5-6)
  - Holy ghost vacuum, or American faints. For organ. (Box 1)
    (Folder 1/7)
  - In my craft or sullen art. For voice and chamber ensemble. (Box 1)
  - Jenny kiss'd me. For voice and piano. (Box 1)
    (Folder 1/8)
  - K. (Box 3)
    (Folder 3/6)
  - K-2., 2 folders (Box 1)
    (Folder 1/9-10)
  - Mod 3. (Box 1)
    (Folder 1/11)
  - Motet. For 4 voices (SATB). (Box 1)
    (Folder 1/12)
  - Moves upon silence. For percussion ensemble., 2 folders (Box 1)
    (Folder 1/13-14)
  - Music for two trumpets and chamber orchestra., 3 folders (Box 3)
    (Folders 3/7-9)
  - [Piano music (Early works)]
    (Folder 4/1)
    - Sherzo[sic] in sixths and thirds Fall 1947 (Box 4)
    - Prelude Fall 1948 (Box 4)
    - Notturno Fall 1948 (Box 4)
    - Prokofieffania scherzo Spring 1949 (Box 4)
    - Lullaby Summer 1949 (Box 4)
    - Unfinished piano trio. (Box 4)
  - Pianopieces. Don Mills, Ont.: BMI Canada circa 1967
    (Folder 5/1)
    - Pianopiece 1. (Box 5)
    - Pianopiece II. (Box 5)
    - Cassiopeia. (Box 5)
    - 19 leaves of performance notes. (Box 5)
  - Pianopiece II. (Box 5)
    (Folder 5/2)
  - Pianopiece 11: informed sources., 2 folders (Box 4)
    (Folders 4/2-3)
  - [Piece for piano] (Box 4)
    (Folder 4/4)
  - [Sonatas, piano], 3 folders (Box 4)
    (include Piano sonata (1951))
    (Folders 4/5-7)
  - [Sonatas, violin] (Box 4)
    (Folder 4/8)
  - Time on time in miracles. For piano, cello and brass instruments.
    (Folder 4/9)
    - [Trios, strings 1960], 4 folders (Box 5)
      (includes Trio for violin, viola and cello. 7 leaves. Incomplete. Contains typewritten note signed by Cacioppo.)
      (Folders 5/3-6)
  - Two pieces for orchestra.
    - Festival overture. (Box 6-7)
    - Overture 1952. (Box 6-7)
    - Overture. (Box 6-7)
    - Overture. (Box 6-7)
    - Overture. (Box 6-7)
    - Overture in F. (Box 6-7)
    - Overture in F. (Box 6-7)
    - Elegy. 1 score (20 p.). (Box 6-7)
  - Two worlds. For chamber ensemble. (Box 5)
    (Folder 5/7)
- Sketches
  - Sketchbooks, 34 items
    - Sketchbooks (Box 8)
    - Sketchbooks (Box 9)
      (continued)
  - Individual unidentified sketches, 6 linear feet
    - Individual unidentified sketches (Box 10)
    - Individual unidentified sketches (Box 11)
- Programs and Program Notes
  - Cacioppo's Programs 1949-1985, 70 items (in 2 folders) (Box 12)
    (Folders 12/1-2)
  - Cacioppo's Program Notes for His Own Music, 21 items (in 2 folders)
    (Folders 12/3-4)
    - Advance of the Fungii, The (Box 12)
    - Bestiary 1: Eingang (Box 12)
    - Holy Ghost Vacuum, or America Faints (Box 12)
    - Mod 3 (Box 12)
    - Pianopiece #1 (Box 12)
    - Pianopiece #2 (Box 12)
    - Pianopiece #3 (Box 12)
    - String Trio (Box 12)
    - Time on Time in Miracles (Box 12)
    - Two Worlds (Box 12)
  - Other Programs and Notes 1949-1983, 116 items (in 3 folders) (Box 12)
    (Folders 12/5-7)
  - Cacioppo's Notes for Other Composers' Programs, 19 items (Box 12)
    (Folder 12/8)
- Correspondence
  - Business and Friends
    - A
      - Abeles, Isaac M., 3 items (Box 12)
      - AhIstrom, David, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Albright, Bill, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Albright, Bill w/ Bekaert postcard, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Anderson, Dennis, 5 items (Box 12)
      - Andrew, Dave, 6 items (Box 12)
      - Ashley, Robert, 9 items (Box 12)
    - B
      - BMI Canada Ltd. (B. J. Wolever), 6 items (Box 12)
      - Banghart, Edward, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Bassett, Leslie, 5 items (Box 12)
      - Bayer, Michael, 4 items (Box 12)
      - Beachler, Kenneth C., 4 items (Box 12)
      - Bekaert, Jacques, 5 items (Box 12)
      - Berman, Ruth and Bill, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Biggerstaff, Ruth, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Blatt, Nina, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Bloomfield, Greg, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Bloor, Andy, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Bolcom, William, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Bordignon, Ida, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Borishansky, Elliot, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Boury, Bob, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Bowers, Stacey, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Bowling Green State University (Marilyn Shrude), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Brennan, Jerry, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Britton, Allen P., 4 items (Box 12)
      - Brown, Anthony, 1 items (Box 12)
    - C-D
      - Cage, John, 1 items (Box 12)
      - California State University, Fullerton (Preston Stedman), 2 items (Box 12)
      - Carraher, Jack, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Cavender, George, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Chase, Gilbert, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Chihara, Paul, 6 items (Box 12)
      - Childs, Barney, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Cionek, Ed, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Clark and Cruickshank (Div. of Bevandol Music Ltd.), 2 items (Box 12)
      - Cogan, Mrs. B. J., 2 items (Box 12)
      - Cohen, Carl, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Composers Recordings, Inc. (Carter Harman), 3 items (Box 12)
      - Composers Recordings, Inc. (Helen Sive), 3 items (Box 12)
      - Crichton, Will, 7 items (Box 12)
      - Cross, Caroline, 4 items (Box 12)
      - Delanghe, Gay, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Doorenbos, Norman J., 1 items (Box 12)
      - Dutton (E. P.) & Co. (Judith Kipnis), 1 items (Box 12)
    - E-G
      - Eynon, Bret, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Exon, George, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Fant, J. Clayton, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Finney, Ross Lee, 4 items (Box 12)
      - Ford Foundation (William H. Nims), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Frieder, Jacqueline, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Funk, Agnes M., 1 items (Box 12)
      - George, Ron, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Glanville-Hicks, Peggy, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Gligaroff, Tom, 13 items (Box 12)
      - Goldstein, Malcolm, 2 items (Box 12)
    - H-K
      - Hargraves, Michael, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Harter, Jean, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Hobson, Arthur, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Hodkinson, Sydney, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Jager, Robert, 1 items (Box 12)
      - James, Richard S., 3 items (Box 12)
      - Janson, TomI item (Box 12)
      - Jehe, Emil and Nama, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Johnson, Mimi, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Johnson, Roger, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Jun, Rose Marie, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Kalellis, Barrett, 7 items (Box 12)
      - Kasemets, Udo, 14 items (Box 12)
      - Klausmeyer, Pete, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Kleiman, Stephen, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Koblitz, David, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Kosagi, Takehisa w/ Bekaert letter, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Kurtz, Eugene, 2 items (Box 12)
    - L-Mumma
      - Lorimer, Michael, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Loudon, Jim, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Lucier, Alvin, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Lum, Sal, 1 items (Box 12)
      - McMillan, Ann, 1 items (Box 12)
      - MaU, Karl, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Manko, Jerry, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Marshall, Stuart, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Martorella, Steve, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Michigan Music Teachers Assoc. (Jere T. Hutcheson), 4 items (Box 12)
      - Mills College (Edward LeFevour), 2 items (Box 12)
      - Monroe Public Schools (Herman J. Dunseith), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Monroe Rotary Club (Emmett V. Cable), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Moore, Barbara, 5 items (Box 12)
      - Moore, Pat, 4 items (Box 12)
      - Mori, Junko S., 2 items (Box 12)
      - Morris, Robert, 12 items (Box 12)
      - Mortner, Richard, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Mumma, Gordon, 23 items (Box 12)
    - Music-N
      - Music for Percussion, Inc. (Bernard Fisher), 2 items (Box 12)
      - National Endowment for the Arts (Walter F. Anderson), 1 items (Box 12)
      - North Carolina School of the Arts (Marie Kroeger), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Northern Illinois University (Terrie A. Anderson), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Northern Illinois University (Stanley Ballinger), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Northern Illinois University (Larry Livingston), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Northern Illinois University (Philip S. Wells), 2 items (Box 12)
      - Northwestern University--ONCE Archive (Don L. Roberts), 3 items (Box 12)
      - Nuemberger, D., 1 items (Box 12)
      - Numus--West Magazine, 1 items (Box 12)
    - O-P
      - Oberlin College (Michael Rosen), 3 items (Box 12)
      - Otte, Al, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Padow, Judith, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Patterson, Willis, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Peck, Russell, 11 items (Box 12)
      - Peltzer, Dwight, 2 items (Box 12)
    - Price, Paul, 23 items (Box 12)
    - R
      - Rapson, Harold C., 2 items (Box 12)
      - Rayle, Jeff, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Reynolds, Roger, 19 items (Box 12)
      - Rodgers, Lloyd, 10 items (Box 12)
      - Ross, Gilbert, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Rotary International (W. Hugh Williams), 1 items (Box 12)
    - S-T
      - Sartori, Guiseppe, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Scavarda, Don, 5 items (Box 12)
      - Sheff, Robert, 4 items (Box 12)
      - Sherwood, Gordon, 19 items (Box 12)
      - Shiffin, Seymour, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Sigma Alpha Iota (Edna Rait Hutton), 3 items (Box 12)
      - Skelly, Steven, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Slauson, Wayne, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Sounds Reasonable (Ed Barnett), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Spitler, R. F., 1 items (Box 12)
      - State University of New York at Stony Brook (Leo Treitter), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Stereo Review (Fred C. Shotwell), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Sutton, Roger, 1 items (Box 12)
      - [Toensing], Dick, 1 items (Box 12)
    - Turetsky, Bertram, 52 items (Box 12)
    - U
      - University of California, Santa Cruz, 2 items (Box 12)
      - University of California, Santa Cruz (Philippa Angelides), 1 items (Box 12)
      - University of California, Santa Cruz (Edward Houghton), 2 items (Box 12)
      - University of Hartford (Edward Diemente), 1 items (Box 12)
      - University of London, 1 items (Box 12)
      - University of Michigan. WUOM, 3 items (Box 12)
      - University of Michigan. WUOM (Neal T. Bedford), 1 items (Box 12)
      - University of Michigan. WUOM (Harvey K. Jacobson), 1 items (Box 12)
      - University of Michigan. WUOM (Evelyn Jessup), 2 items (Box 12)
      - University of Michigan. WUOM (Fred and Ethel Lee), 1 items (Box 12)
      - University of Michigan. WUOM (Dr. Nathan), 1 items (Box 12)
      - University of Michigan. WUOM (William L. Tobey), 1 items (Box 12)
      - University of Southern California (Halsey Stevens), 1 items (Box 12)
    - V-Z
      - Vinton, John, 2 items (Box 12)
      - Waltzer, Neil, 6 items (Box 12)
      - Weigel, Eugene, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Weiss, Edward, 3 items (Box 12)
      - Weitzel, Sarah, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Western Michigan University (Robert R. Fink), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Wigle, James, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Wilding-White, Ray, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Wilhelm, Ross, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Wisconsin State University (Robert Samarotto), 1 items (Box 12)
      - Wong, 1 items (Box 12)
      - Zwiazek Kompzytorow Polskich, 1 items (Box 12)
    - Unidentified letters, 17 items (Box 12)
  - Mother-Chronological 1946-1971, 361 items (in 19 folders) (Box 12)
    (contains newspaper clippings from letters)
  - Other Family Letters-Chronological 1939-1981, 65 items (in 3 folders) (Box 13)
- Newspaper Clippings, Biographical Material and Photographs
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Newspaper clippings about Cacioppo, 25 items (Box 13)
    - Newspaper clippings about other people, 83 items (Box 13)
  - Biographical Material
    - Addresses, etc.
      - Addresses and phone numbers (Box 13)
      - Autobiographical Search Game, 1 items (Box 13)
      - Biographies and other personal information, 15 items (Box 13)
      - Certificate of Acceptability (USAF), 1 items (Box 13)
      - Coat of Arms: Historiography, 1 items (Box 13)
    - Vitae
      - Curriculum Vitae in Cacioppo's handwriting, 1 items (Box 13)
      - Typewritten copy with Cacioppo's corrections, 1 items (Box 13)
      - Clean typewritten copy, 1 items (Box 13)
    - Lists, etc., 2 folders
      - List of Books from George E. Cacioppo's Estate, 1 items (Box 13)
      - List of Music from George E. Cacioppo's Estate, 1 items (Box 13)
      - List of Music Scores from George E. Cacioppo's Estate, 1 items (Box 13)
      - Music at Michigan Faculty Biographies, 1 items (Box 13)
      - Music for Percussion Catalog, 1 items (Box 13)
      - Obituary notices and memorial concerts, 6 items (Box 13)
      - Recipe for "Pasta con Piselli", 1 items (Box 13)
      - University of Michigan Certificate, 1 items (Box 13)
      - University of Michigan Transcripts, 3 items (Box 13)
  - Photographs
    - Portrait of Cacioppo, 1 items (Box 15)
    - Caricatures of Cacioppo, 2 items (Box 13)
    - Photographs of Cacioppo, family and friends, 121 items (Box 13)
- ONCE Festival Materials 1961-1969
  - Oversize posters, 19 items (Box 15)
  - Oversize posters, brochures and programs, 88 items (Box 16)
  - Archive inventory, Crosstalk Intermedia, fliers, programs, Dramatic Arts Center material and WUOM program guides, 62 items (in 7 folders) (Box 13)
  - Newspaper clippings, 6 items (Box 13)
- Cacioppo's Class Notes and Writings
  - Class notes
    - Computer science (Box 13)
    - Orchestration exercises (Box 17)
    - Counterpoint exercises (Box 13)
    - Music analyses (Box 13)
    - Sheet music for music analysis class (Box 13)
  - Lectures, essays and other writings
    - Essays on Bartok and Beethoven (Box 13)
    - Essays on counterpoint, musicology and Verdi (Box 13)
    - Double Lecture (Box 13)
    - Music topics for seminars and classes, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Creative writings, 4 folders (Box 14)
- Writings by Others
  - Other people's creative writing (Box 14)
  - Course handouts (English) (Box 14)
  - Combinatonality by Robert Morris (Box 14)
  - Pitch Relations I-HI by Robert Morris, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Flute Thesis by Anne Aitcheson. (Box 14)
  - Psychology--Willison Crichton (Box 14)
  - Robert Ashley (Box 14)
  - Gordon Mumma (Box 14)
  - Articles by Hitchcock, Mumma and Johnson (Box 14)
- Published Journals and Articles Owned by Cacioppo
  - A. Journals owned by Cacioppo
    - "Musical Sources as Graphic Works." arts canada, 25, no. 2 ( June 1968 ) pp. 27-28. (Box 14)
    - Behrman, David. "Why Modem Music Looks Strange." Bandwagon, 13, no. 5 ( November 1965 ), pp. 14-17. (Box 14)
    - Kasemets, Udo. "Music of the nineteen sixties and after: George Cacioppo" Canavang, ( 1968 ), pp. 24-31. (Box 14)
    - Bekaert, Jacques. "Troisieme programme." cles pour la musique, no. 27 ( Mars 1971 ), pp. 20-21. (Box 14)
    - Human Resource Management, 16, no. 1 ( Spring 1977 ). (Box 14)
    - "Level I: Life Styles Interpretation." Human Synergistics ( 1978 ) (Box 14)
    - Grofsorean, Michael. "Time on Time." lightworks, no. 6 ( December-January 1977 ), pp. 5-7. (Box 17)
    - Kasemets, Udo. "Current Chronicle-United States: Ann Arbor." Musical Quarterly, 50, no. 4 ( October 1964 ), pp. 515-519. (Box 14)
    - "New Music of Merit." Pan Pipes of Sigma Alpha Iota, 61, no. 2 ( January 1969 ), pp. 8-13. (Box 14)
    - Bekaert, Jacques. "Ann Arbor, ville de province." La Releve, 26, no. 38 ( September 19, 1970 ), p. 12. (Box 14)
    - "Cassiopeia." cover La Releve, 26, no. 51-52 ( December 19, 1970 ). (Box 14)
  - B. Articles owned by Cacioppo
    - "American Center for Students and Artists." 1963-1964 Concert Season. (Box 14)
    - "Digital Keyboard Sounds Like the Real Thing." News releases about the Kurzweil 250 Synthesizer. (Box 14)
    - Donatoni, Franco. Program notes: "For Grilly (Improvvisazione per 7)." (Box 14)
    - Errante, F. Gerard. "Contemporary Aspects of Clarinet Performance." Outline. (Box 14)
    - Feldman, Morton. "Boola Boola." (Box 14)
    - Gabura, James. "Computer Control of Sound Apparatus for Electomic Music." Paper presented at the 33rd Convention October 16-October 19, 1967 of the Audio Engineering Society. (Box 14)
    - "GyorgyLigeti." Record jacket notes. (Box 14)
    - Highwater, Jamake. "Music on Video." (Box 14)
    - Kirk, Roger E. "Difference Limen for Tone Diminution." Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 30, no. 10 ( October 1958 ): 915-918. (Box 14)
    - Kirk, Roger E. "Tuning Preferences for Piano Unison Groups." Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 31, no. 12 ( December 1959 ): 1644-48. (Box 14)
    - Krumm, Philip. "New Sounds and What to Do With Them." (Box 14)
    - "Leonard Bernstein Conducts Music of Our Time." Record jacket notes. (Box 14)
    - Lorimer, Michael. Notes about his guitar composition. (Box 14)
    - Martin, Daniel W. "Decay Rates of Piano Tones." Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 19, no. 4 ( July 1947 ): 535-541. (Box 14)
    - Martin, D. W., and W. D. Ward. "Subjective Evaluation of Musical Scale Temperament in Pianos." Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 33, no. 5 ( May 1961 ): 582-85. (Box 14)
    - Mumma, Gordon. "Technology in the Modem Arts: Music & Theatre." (Box 14)
    - O'Neill, Catherine. "A Modem Composer Whose Rhythms Ride the Ages." Chronicle Review ( November 13,1978 ). (Box 14)
    - Page, Tim. "Steve Reich's Music for 18 Musicians, Finally Gets a Good Treatment on Vinyl." Columbian Spectrum, 103, no. 35 ( November 2, 1978 ). (Box 14)
    - "Piano References in Journal of the Acoustical Society from Cumulative Indices of the Journal." Bibliography (Box 14)
    - "Piano References Not in Journal of the Acoustical Society from Cumulative Indices of the Journal." Bibliography. (Box 14)
    - Pinkerton, Richard C. "Information Theory and Melody." Scientific America 194, no. 2 ( February 1956 ). (Box 14)
    - Porter, Andrew. "Musical Events." New Yorker, ( November 6, 1978 ). (Box 14)
    - Price, Paul. "Percussion Up-to-Date." Music Journal ( December 1964 ). (Box 14)
    - [Program notes for sound recording of unidentified contemporary composer]. (Box 14)
    - Rich, Alan. "Down to Essentials." New York (November 6,1978). (Box 14)
    - Rockwell, John. "The Pop Life." New York Times (November 17, 1978). (Box 14)
    - Rockwell, John. "Video Portraits of Avant-Garde Composers." New York Times (May 29,1977). (Box 14)
    - Sherwood, Gordon. "Curriculum Vitae and Chronological List of Works." (Box 14)
    - Smalley, Roger. "Experimental Music." (Box 14)
    - Sullivan, Mark. "Music of Steve Reich and the Music of Ghana: A Comparison." (Box 14)
    - Vega, Aurelio de Ia. "Regarding Electronic Music." Tempo, ( Winter 1965-66 ): 2-11. (Box 14)
    - Ward, W. D., and D. W. Martin. "Psychophysical Comparison of Just Tuning and Equal Temperament in Sequences of Individual Tones." Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 33, no. 5 ( May 1961 ): 586-88. (Box 14)
- Miscellaneous Materials
  - A. WUOM
    - Materials from WUOM Desk, 9 items (Box 14)
    - News Releases by Cacioppo, 26 items (Box 14)
  - B. Grate Society, 5 items (Box 14)
  - C. Other News Releases, 1 items (Box 14)
- Sound Recordings
  - Cacioppo recordings
    - Nocturne: In Memoriam Bela Bartok, 5 in. reel, 5:25, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 1]
    - String Trio, 5 in. reel, half-track monaural, 19 cm/sec (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 2]
    - Revised Trio, 7 in. reel (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 3]
    - Bestiary I: Eingang, 5 in. reel, 7:00, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 4]
    - Bestiary, 7 in. reel (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 5]
    - Piano Piece #1, 5 in. reel (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 6]
    - Cassiopeia
      - Cassiopeia in New York, Takes 1-2, Take 1 (10:34) and 2 (10:40), 7 in. reel, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 7]